well well well what do we have here two
solid kettlebells that could turn up the
heat in the weight room like a broken ac
unit i've got one from rogue i've got
one from on it but you know how this
goes there could only be one which one's
gonna be crowned the champion
stick around and we'll find out
what's up everybody it's jake and of
course i'm in the barbing garage gym and
today i've got a kettlebell from rogue
and one from on it in this review i'm
gonna compare the two and help you
decide which one is best for you but
before i get going we've reviewed a lot
of kettlebells on barbin.com and if you
want to browse our best list just simply
search barbind best kettlebells our list
is going to pull right up for you and
you can decide which one is best for you
specifically
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the
similarities between these two
kettlebells first and foremost these are
26 pound kettlebells
neither one of these are available in a
full set neither company offers that so
you definitely can go and purchase as
many as you want but you might wind up
spending more money in the long run
because you don't have a designated set
to choose from like you do with some
other companies these are also not
competition kettlebells so the size is
going to increase as you go up in weight
so if you're somebody who wants your
kettlebells to be uniform in size
regardless of their weight go get you
some competition kettlebells both of
these kettlebells do have a powder coat
finish
just going to give it a nice grip on its
own but you can definitely use some
chalk it's going to mix well with both
of these kettlebells
you have color-coded handles just gonna
make it super easy in terms of going and
selecting which weight you want but you
also have engravings on the back with
both of these in kilograms and pounds
just to make sure especially in the
beginning as you're learning what each
color means that you're getting the
right kettlebell neither one of these
are coated in rubber so it's gonna be
really easy to store on their flat base
there's no seam there's nothing in the
way that's gonna possibly make them
lopsided but because they're not coated
in rubber it might not be ideal for you
if you're working out in your living
room maybe a different room of your home
because you definitely don't want to
drop these it might you know put a hole
in your floor and i highly doubt you
want that but with that being said
definitely don't just drop some rubber
coated kettlebells because the same
thing could happen to you could cause
some damage you don't want that also
both of these are one single piece so
you don't have to worry about the handle
and the bell coming loose over time with
either one of these because they're not
welded together there's no plugs no pins
like you often find with kettlebells
that are made of lesser quality you
don't have that here you shouldn't have
to worry about that whatsoever
[Music]
okay so while it might not look like it
at that first initial glance both of
these kettlebells are in fact different
so let's talk about the powder coat
finish first yeah they both have it but
with on it you're looking at more of a
shine here as opposed to that matte
finish with rogue now i don't think this
is gonna change anything about your
experience with either one of these
kettlebells i think that's just gonna be
personal preference and that aesthetic
that you're looking for for your home
gym
i wasn't able to find the exact
dimensions of the handle diameter with
on it but with rogue this 26 pound bail
is 1.4 inches in diameter and it
definitely feels thicker in my hands as
opposed to this on it one so if you do
have some pretty big hands wide palms
you might want to go with the one from
rogue because i think they're going to
be
thicker
throughout all the weight options the
color-coded handles here are also pretty
significantly different with rogue this
blue really pops out at you in my eyes
but with on it i mean it's there you can
still see that it's there just kind of a
little bit tougher to see i don't know
if that's going to be the case all the
other colors but with this blue
specifically you're kind of dealing with
that
now they also
both have a flat base but
it's pretty easy to tell that with on it
you have a wider base now
that might make it a little bit easier
in terms of storage it might decrease
the chances of it kind of wobbling maybe
even toppling over as you set it down
super fast it's just something worth
remembering okay so rogue also has more
weight options for you to choose from so
they have 18 different options for you
to choose from from nine pounds up to
203 pounds while with on it you're
working with eight different options
from 13 to 70 pounds now rogue's also
charging you more for their kettlebells
okay so
for instance this 26 pound kettlebell
from rogue it's going to cost you around
60 bucks while this 26 pounder from on
it that's going to run you right around
and as you go on their website to kind
of compare and contrast it's the case
for every single similar weight option
you're going to be saving money with on
it but remember you do have more weight
options with rogue so if you do need
something super heavy maybe even a
little bit on the lighter side rogue's
going to be your way to go in regards to
that
[Music]
okay so as i mentioned you are going to
be spending more money if you were to go
with rogue but let's compare that a
little bit more now if you head to both
of their websites you kind of compare
and contrast between the two and the
similar weight options you're gonna find
that you're gonna be spending around 20
to 30 bucks every single time with rogue
now i'll give you a few examples here so
a 13-pound kettlebell from rogue it's
going to cost you around 45 bucks while
with on it it's gonna be about 20. once
again this 26 pound kettlebell from
rogue is running running around 60 bucks
and it's about 40 bucks on it the 53
pound kettlebell from rogue it's about
90 bucks or so
compared to about 75 76 with on it and
since on it does cap out at 70 pounds
it'll be the last one here it's gonna
run you about 90 bucks or so with on it
as opposed to 125
roughly with rogue so if you are looking
to save some money i would suggest going
with on it because the quality is nearly
identical they're about neck and neck in
my opinion but like i said you get to
save money on every single similar
weight option now they don't feel too
different in my hands despite that wider
handle from rogue so if you're not too
particular about your grip that you're
getting from a kettlebell maybe you
think they're about all the same once
again go and save some money with on it
but if you are particular about that you
know especially this wider grip and
maybe you're just you know partial to
rogue in general then maybe you won't
mind spending a little bit of extra
money for something that you personally
like
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
that went into both of these kettlebells
i'm gonna start with rogue fortunately
they do in fact have the exact handle
diameters for each individual
weight option which once again does
range from nine pounds up to 203 pounds
all right so for the nine to 18 pound
kettlebells you're gonna find that
handle diameter to be 1.2 inches this 26
pound kettlebell that handle is 1.4
inches in diameter the 35 to 88 pound
bells those are 1.5 inches in diameter
and the handles on the 97 to 203 pound
kettlebells are 1.5 inches in diameter
these kettlebells were made from a first
run iron ore it's gonna be super durable
it's gonna last you a really long time
might even be the last one you ever need
to purchase you don't have to worry
about the handle or the bell coming
loose because it is in fact one solid
piece which is a nice touch you do have
a nice powder coat here it's a matte
black finish it looks pretty good but
the main thing here is that it's going
to give you a nice solid grip for your
workouts it's going to work well with
chalk too i really like how much this
color coding pops out at you makes it
really easy just to make sure you're
getting the exact weight that you want
and get right to working out but if you
do ever get confused especially in the
beginning it is nice that there are
engravings on the back just to let you
know you are in fact you know in this
case picking up 26 pound kettlebell
okay so let's talk about the build with
on it now once again i could not find
those exact handle diameters for you
guys but in this case between these two
26 pound kettlebells like i said it's
thinner than this one from rogue so if
you have big hands you might not like
that it might be you know overlapping a
little bit and that's probably not going
to give you the best grip you could be
looking for just something to remember
these kettlebells were made with a
gravity casting process so essentially
that's just going to make sure that
weight is evenly distributed throughout
the entire kettlebell and that each
option is exactly like pinpoint accuracy
with what is advertised on each
kettlebell
you do have color-coded handles here
it doesn't pop out as much with this
blue specifically as it does with rogue
but it's still there you can still see
which weight is what it makes a
difference you can easily tell but if
you get confused in the beginning you
know you do have engravings on the back
just to help you out a little bit
i really like the flat base right here
it might make it optimal in terms of
storage
make it super easy just to store it's
not going to topple over on you or
wobble at all and this powder coat right
here yeah it's more of a shine than it
is with the one with rogue it's still
going to give you a nice grip it's not
going to take that away and you can also
use chalk it's going to work well with
this kettlebell if you want it to
the weight does range from nine pounds
up to 203 pounds and i almost forgot but
i have to mention it this powder coat is
also chip resistant so if you drop it on
a hard surface your chances of chipping
it should be obsolete
[Music]
okay so making a decision between these
two kettlebells might be a little bit
difficult for you but it's really i
think going to boil down to two
different things personal preference on
how they feel in your hands as well as
how much money you're going to be
spending on these kettlebells so
quality of these two they're nearly
identical like i said they're about neck
and neck
they're both made from one single piece
of iron the handle on the bell or like i
said one single piece so you shouldn't
have to worry about them ever coming
loose over time like you often have to
do with you know kettlebells made of
lesser quality so both of these should
last you the majority of your workout
experience possibly your entire life
which is really nice but i like how onit
used a gravity casting process
for their kettlebells that weight is
going to be pinpoint accurate with what
it's listed as on the website and
obviously engraved on the kettlebell
that's not to say that's the case with
rogue i mean obviously rogue makes very
good products but i don't know for a
fact if they do use the gravity casting
process so just to make sure that the
weight is exactly what you think it is
you know this case 26 pounds you might
want to weigh it when you get it at home
just to make sure
now me personally
you know obviously for the sake of this
video i have to choose between one of
these two kettlebells i'm gonna have to
go with on it like i said the quality
it's just as good but i'm gonna save
money in the long run as opposed to
rogue now that's the case if i you know
where to stop at 70 pounds if i go over
than that
i'm gonna have to go elsewhere you know
rogue does offer you more options both
heavier and actually a little bit
lighter than on it does
now i guess you could say even up to 70
pounds i'm only saving about 20 to 30
bucks per kettlebell that's including
shipping so that might not matter to you
if money is not much of an issue then
yeah maybe you do want to go with rogue
it is a popular brand it does give you a
nice grip that handle is thicker than
this 26 pound one from on it i don't
know for a fact if on it eventually
catch up with the thickness of rogues
but that's something to think about too
so
once again it's really just going to
boil down to personal preference and if
you don't care about the money you're
spending then yeah maybe you do want to
go with the rogue kettlebell
[Music]
all right well that's a wrap on today's
comparison over the rogue kettlebell and
the onyx kettlebell honestly y'all these
are two really good options for you to
choose from they're built to last
because they are in fact one single
piece of iron like i said you don't have
to worry about the handle and the bell
ever coming loose over time that powder
coat is going to give you a nice grip on
its own plus it's going to work well
with chalk
but once again if i absolutely had to
choose between these two kettlebells i'm
gonna have to go with on it
i like the fact that i'm saving some
money
i like the flat base right here i think
it's gonna help me out in terms of
storage and plus i like that they use a
gravity casting process
just knowing that the weight is exactly
what it says it is once again that's not
to say
it's not going to be the case with rogue
but i do know for a fact that annette
used a gravity cast so i'm getting what
i asked for
thanks for watching everybody i hope
this video helped you out as you look to
add a trusty kettlebell or maybe a
couple to your home gym
as always stay on the lookout for my
next review but for now why don't you
head over to barbind.com and you can
read more about the comparison between
these two kettlebells just search bar
bend rogue kettlebell verse on it
kettlebell you can read more into detail
about what i discussed with you today
now i'm gonna go swing these bad boys
around i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
you